NISHAT ANJUM

□+8801723124778 | Image: Imag

Summary_

Principal Software Engineer with a decade of impressive background in designing and developing enterprise-level software solutions. My expertise lies in JAVA and JVM-based technology stacks, software design patterns, and development methodologies. After scrutinizing my passion, comprehensive work experience, and definitive ambition, I have decided to pursue a research route Master's Program in the field of Software Engineering, which I believe will lead me to a career as a Computer and Software Specialist in the future.

Education 2.

University of Dhaka Dhaka, Bangladesh

BSc. (Honours) in Computer Science and Engineering

2007 - 2011

- CGPA: 3.37/4.00 (3.40 in last two academic years)
- Merit Position: 14th out of 45 students
- Courses: Software Engineering, Data Structures and Algorithms, Computer Programming Language, Database Management System, Operating System, Computer Networks, Data Communication, Discrete Mathematics, Theory of Computation, Artificial Intelligence
- **IELTS**: Overall Band Score **7.5** [L-9, R-7.5, W-7, S-6.5]

Research Interests_

Software Engineering, Empirical Software Engineering, Application of Machine Learning in Software Engineering, Database and knowledge-base systems, Data Mining, Data Visualization, Human Computer Interaction.

Academic Research 🗷

Title: Throughput Maximization in Device to Device(D2D) Enabled Cellular Network

University Of Dhaka

Supervisor: Professor DR. MD. ABDUR RAZZAQUE

2012

In this work, We addressed the spectrum-sharing problem between cellular and underlaying D2D communication. Our main goal was
to maximize the throughput of the underlying 3G cellular network in non-orthogonal Resource-Sharing mode. We proposed a Scheduled
resource-sharing Algorithm for eNodeB that intelligently identified potential D2D connection pairs and optimally shared UpLink and DownLink resources by calculating SINR for each pair.

Technical Expertise ____

Language: Java, Python, C/C++, JavaScript, TypeScript, R

Frameworks: Spring-[Boot, Security, MVC, Webflow, Data JPA, Batch, HATEOAS, GraphQL], Python Flask, Angular, Hibernate, JPA, Mockito

Web Services: REST, SOAP

Middlewares: WebLogic, WildFly, Tomcat, TomcatEE, Glassfish

Databases: MySQL, Oracle, PostgreSQL, In-memory Data Structure Store-REDIS, Cloud Object Storage - MINIO

Tools: Maven, Gradle, Ant, Postman, Git, Bitbucket, Docker

OS Platforms: Linux, Windows, Mac

Big Data: Kafka, Apache KUDU, Apache Spark, Apache Druid, Elasticsearch

Work Experience_

Tiger IT Bangladesh Limited. 🗹

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Principal Software Engineer

Oct 2022 - present

- Supervising and training a Development team of four software engineers.
- Providing technical guidance to the team and overseeing the technical aspects of four Government projects and upcoming Projects.
- Improving the performance of existing software solutions.
- $\bullet \ \ \text{Investigating Project-related objections and taking necessary measurements to ensure optimal software performance.}$
- Regularly attend team meetings to discuss projects, brainstorm ideas, and propose solutions to any issues.
- Designing, coding, and debugging new projects.

Senior Software Engineer

Oct 2019 - Sept 2022

- Supervised a team of four software engineers to ascertain the successful completion of deliverables of four country-scale projects.
- · Performed various RnD and provided expert support and guidance on architectural changes in ongoing initiatives taken by the company.
- · Continuously contributed to troubleshooting issues in production deployment and performance tuning.
- · Reviewed code for defects and quality against technical documents and standard practices.
- · Designing, coding, and debugging new projects

Software Engineer Dec 2015 - Sept 2019

- Extensively re-engineered legacy software system to improve scalability and increased performance by approximately 35%.
- · Core architect of a large-scale data migration project involving a highly complex process that successfully migrated approximately 120M Demographic and Biometric data within 42 hours.
- Developed High volume and low latency Restful APIs for various client applications serving **responses less than 30ms.**
- Developed data streaming pipeline using Apache Kafka that combine messaging and storage of both historical and real-time data.
- Developed a high-performance real-time fast data Analytics application using Apache Druid, Kudu, and Kafka.
- Designed and developed Report modules for multiple ongoing projects which involved complex query writing.
- Assisted the Junior Software Engineers in solving technical problems and mentored them in writing high-quality code.

Therap BD Ltd. 🗹 Dhaka, Bangladesh

Associate Software Engineer

Oct 2014 - Dec 2015

- Worked with Technical Staff to understand problems with software and correct them.
- Developed new features for the MAR module of The Therap application.
- Wrote a successful migration script incorporating ETL process to store lookup standard diagnosis codes (e.g. ICD-9/10).
- Solved user reported bugs of different modules in the Therap Application.
- · Learning and experimenting the usability of various technologies in The Therap application.

Junior Software Engineer

Jan 2013 - Sept 2014

- · Learning, installing and reviewing various technologies related to software development.
- Investigated users reported bugs in the codebase and resolved them.
- Did code refactoring to increase readability and performance in different modules.

Industrial Projects 🗷

Bangladesh NID application System

TigerIT Bangladesh

Technology Stack: [Spring MVC, Spring Security, JSP, Semactic-UI, JQuery]

· An online public portal where citizen of Bangladesh can apply for NID card and voter registration

Rohingya AFIS And AFRS adjudication System

TigerIT Bangladesh

Technology Stack: [Python Flusk, Angular.js, Spring Boot, Ouartz Scheduler]

· An application which ceaselessly verifies new voter applications with Rohingya AFIS and AFRS database

CMS system for Election Commission Officials

TigerIT Bangladesh

Technology Stack: [Spring Boot, Spring Security, JWT Token, JSP, Bootstrap, vue.js]

Web Application for bangladesh election commission officials to oversee voter registration and NID card applications

Bangladesh Citizen data Migration Project

TigerIT Bangladesh

Technology Stack: [Spring Boot-Scheduling, JDBC, Apache Kafka, Redis]

 A data migration project to migration 120M voter demographic and biometric data to elasticsearch, Apache KUDU, Redis, Minio and Oracle database.

Nepal HSENP Registration System

TigerIT Bangladesh

Technology Stack: [Spring MVC, Spring Security, JSP, Semactic UI, JQuery]

· A online public portal where Nepal Citizen can apply for high security embossed number plate for their Vehicles.

Nepal HSENP Application management System

TigerIT Bangladesh

Technology Stack: [Spring MVC, Spring Security, Thymeleaf, Bootstrap, JQuery, Oracle database]

• A web application for nepal DOTM officials to supervise HSENP printing applications.

Nepal vehicle data migration project

TigerIT Bangladesh

Technology Stack: [Spring-Batch, Spring-Jdbc, Oracle Database]

A data migration projects to migrate 35M vehicle data to Oracle database.

Bangladesh NTMC National Datahub Project

TigerIT Bangladesh

Technology Stack: [Spring Boot, Spring Security, JWT Token, Apache Kafka, Redis, GraphQL]

An ETL project for bangladesh NTMC which accumulate Citizen data from multiple sources and make them accessible for

Vehicle Tracking System - Banngladesh NTMC

TigerIT Bangladesh

Technology Stack: [Alient JAVA SDK, MQTT, Caffeine Cache, Spring Boot, Spring Scheduling]

· The application unceasingly accumulates vehicle movement information by interfacing with Alien RFID Reader

Therap Application Technology Stack: [Spring MVC, JSP, EJB, Hibernate JPA, Oracle Database] Therap BD Ltd.

- · Developed new feature in Medication Administration Record(MAR) module to record patient medication record
- Developed a migration project to store lookup standard ICD-9/10 diagnosis code into relational Database

Academic Projects_____

Buddy Circle-A Social networking web application

University Of Dhaka

Internet Programming

• An application developed back in 2012 using spring mvc, jsp, html5, jpa, mysql

Tic Tac Toe Game using ATmega32 microcontroller

University Of Dhaka

Computer Peripherals and Interfacing

2010

2012

A multiplayer tic-tac-toe game written in C language for ATmega32 Controller

Dots and Boxes - Online Multiplayer Game

Object Oriented Programming-JAVA

• An online multiplayer game developed using JAVA Applet and socket programming

Avoid collision Game University Of Dhaka

Programming Language Fundamental- C Language

• A simple single player game developed using C i-Graphics library

Unix Shell University Of Dhaka

Operating System

• A simple bash like Unix shell which executed linux command using exec().

Competition and Achievements_____

2015	Runner-Up , Women Table Tennis Tournament arranged by Therap BD. Ltd.	Dhaka, Bangladesh
2007	Education Board Scholarship, HSC Board Exam	Rajshahi, Bangladesh
2005	Education Board Scholarship, SSC Board Exam	Rajshahi, Bangladesh

Interests_

Table Tennis Table Tennis is my favorite sport of all. I play table tennis with my colleagues every day at my workplace. Workout I am a fitness freak. Some of my favorite activities are western yoga, low-impact aerobics, and Zumba.

Cooking I love baking and Cooking. Baking my birthday cake gives me ultimate joy. I try out new recipes every weekend. **Traveling** I am an avid traveler. I travel around in my own country and abroad whenever I find a possible opportunity.

Music I enjoy almost all types of music. However, primarily I love Soul, Country, Indi, pop, Psychedelic, OST, and K-Pop.

Languages.

English Professional proficiency Bengali Native proficiency Hindi Bilingual proficiency

University Of Dhaka

2008